<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data science | PBP</title>
    <link>/category/data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_huf38a19245be9241b383ddd5efc4c0577_101791_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Data science</title>
      <link>/category/data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 20 YouTube Channels to Learn Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/top-20-youtube-channels-for-datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/top-20-youtube-channels-for-datascience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knew YouTube would become so influential in our lives when it was launched back in 2005? Today after 15 years, it is known to be the best platform from which millions of people all around the world get enlighten with anything that anyone can possibly think of. There are thousands popular of YouTube channels out there today. But are there any dedicated YouTube channels for developers do you know about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even all the stats and number says it all about the popularity of YouTube in today’s time. And it didn’t take too long to become the second most popular website of the world right after its giant partner Google. Today one can find the YouTube app in every known device, starting from smartphones, tablets to a smart television, and any other streaming devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As this platform is a part of all our lives now so many people simply creating and sharing videos for it made fortune out of it. And today many YouTube channels have become really popular for a number of reasons. Now the medium &amp;amp; reach of YouTube has become so big &amp;amp; vast that this is a place where you can get audiences for anything that you want to teach or share useful&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today we are going to highlight some of the most prominent Data Science based YouTube channels for developers. But also for the general non-techy learners So keep reading to get introduced with some of the most famous YouTube channels dedicated mostly to Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;You Tube Channels&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Tech with Tim&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11. 365Data Science&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2. Sentdex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12. Edureka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. Corey Schafer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13. Data School&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4. Python Programmer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14. Data Camp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5. Keith Gali&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15. Siraj Raval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. Andreas Kretz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16. Great learning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7. Free Code Camp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17. Krish Naik&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8. Springboard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18. David Langer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Data Science Dojo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19. StatQuest with Josh Stamer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10. 3Blue1Brown&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20. CS Dojo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study: Analytics and Data Science Jobs in India: June 2021</title>
      <link>/post/analytics-datascience-aims/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/analytics-datascience-aims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;C:%5CUsers%5Cresearch%5CDocuments%5Cimage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-analytics-job-report-presented-by-analytics-india-magazine-aim-provides-a-broad-study-of-the-data-science-job-landscape--covering-profiles-and-roles-that-require-analytics-competencies-and-skills&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The analytics job report, presented by Analytics India Magazine (AIM), provides a broad study of the data science job landscape – covering profiles and roles that require analytics competencies and skills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;report&#34;&gt;Report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research provides a comprehensive view of the talent market that was affected by the Covid-19 pandemic and its recovery since the lockdown restrictions were lifted. The report highlights the upswing in analytics jobs in the post-pandemic world and factors that have led to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report also outlines which functional analytics skills and programming languages are currently most in-demand in the market. The report provides insights for recruiters and hiring companies to study the demand for skills across the analytics function. They can identify and close any capability gaps across workforces. By highlighting the talent hotspots in the country, the report enables organization&amp;rsquo;s to build a steady talent pipeline from various regions or cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​	This Job Study is a holistic analysis of the Indian Analytics and Data Science jobs and skills landscape. This study/report covers the top job trends in the analytics space, specifically open jobs at a given point in time. It provides a detailed break-up and analysis of jobs by certain criteria, such as cities, industries, experience levels, technologies/tools, and salary hierarchies. The report provides details and analysis of the types of companies that are recruiting key talent in the data science domain. The report identifies reasons for significant shifts or changes in hiring trends across the criteria defined above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;top-trends-in-analytics-and-data-science&#34;&gt;Top Trends in Analytics and Data Science&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Data Science Job Trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs by Cities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs By Sector Or Industry (Excluding Analytics Jobs In The IT Sector)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience Requirement For Analytics Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs By Tools &amp;amp; Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salaries Advertised For Analytics Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs By Company Type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are approximately &lt;strong&gt;138,000 jobs open in June 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, a 67.0% increase from June 2020 when the average of advertised analytics jobs reached the lowest due to the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This increase in job numbers can be mainly attributed to the backfilling activity of companies after they laid off many employees due to the lockdown in March 2020. It can also be attributed to the accelerated adoption of AI/data science in India, which is a direct result of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1xfefhElGqwHQ4wSUQFmLUTQGkd7aDBsZ/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the Report here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please find reports from previous years here:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-2020-by-great-learning-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-2019-by-great-learning-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-2018-by-edvancer-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/analytics-and-data-science-india-jobs-study-2017-by-edvancer-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-april-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Originally Published in AIM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
