<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | PBP</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_huf38a19245be9241b383ddd5efc4c0577_101791_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Data Visualization Blogs to Follow</title>
      <link>/post/best-data-visualization-blogs-to-follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/best-data-visualization-blogs-to-follow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consuming large sets of data isn’t always straightforward. Sometimes, data sets are so large that it’s downright impossible to discern anything useful from them. That’s where data visualizations come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating data visualizations is rarely straightforward. It’s not as if designers can simply take a data set with thousands of entries and create a visualization from scratch. Sure, it’s possible, but who wants to spend dozens or hundreds of hours plotting dots on a scatter chart? That’s where data visualization tools come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re at all familiar with data analysis, then you’ve encountered data visualization. It is a key part of data analysis. We’ll explain how it is used and discuss each of the different types of visualizations, but first let’s make sure we all understand what it is and why it’s important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none d-xl-none &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-data-visualization-tools&#34;&gt;What Are Data Visualization Tools?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-data-visualization-and-why-is-it-important&#34;&gt;What is data visualization and why is it important?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why-do-we-need-data-visualization&#34;&gt;Why do we need data visualization?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-is-data-visualization-used&#34;&gt;How is data visualization used?&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#types-of-data-visualization-charts&#34;&gt;Types of data visualization charts&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#here-is-the-list-of-the-blogs-to-follow&#34;&gt;Here is the list of the Blogs to follow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-data-visualization-tools&#34;&gt;What Are Data Visualization Tools?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization tools provide data visualization designers with an easier way to create visual representations of large data sets. When dealing with data sets that include hundreds of thousands or millions of data points, automating the process of creating a visualization at least in part, makes a designer’s job significantly easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data visualizations can then be used for a variety of purposes: dashboards, annual reports, sales and marketing materials, investor slide decks, and virtually anywhere else information needs to be interpreted immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-data-visualization-and-why-is-it-important&#34;&gt;What is data visualization and why is it important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization is the representation of data or information in a graph, chart, or other visual format. It communicates relationships of the data with images. This is important because it allows trends and patterns to be more easily seen. With the rise of big data upon us, we need to be able to interpret increasingly larger batches of data. Machine learning makes it easier to conduct analyses such as predictive analysis, which can then serve as helpful visualizations to present. But data visualization is not only important for data scientists and data analysts, it is necessary to understand data visualization in any career. Whether you work in finance, marketing, tech, design, or anything else, you need to visualize data. That fact showcases the importance of data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-we-need-data-visualization&#34;&gt;Why do we need data visualization?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need data visualization because a visual summary of information makes it easier to identify patterns and trends than looking through thousands of rows on a spreadsheet. It’s the way the human brain works. Since the purpose of data analysis is to gain insights, data is much more valuable when it is visualized. Even if a data analyst can pull insights from data without visualization, it will be more difficult to communicate the meaning without visualization. Charts and graphs make communicating data findings easier even if you can identify the patterns without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In undergraduate business schools, students are often taught the importance of presenting data findings with visualization. Without a visual representation of the insights, it can be hard for the audience to grasp the true meaning of the findings. For example, rattling off numbers to your boss won’t tell them why they should care about the data, but showing them a graph of how much money the insights could save/make them is sure to get their attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-data-visualization-used&#34;&gt;How is data visualization used?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization has many uses. Each type of data visualization can be used in different ways. We’ll get into the different types in a moment, but for now, here are some of the most common ways data visualization is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;changes-over-time&#34;&gt;Changes over time&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps the most basic and common use of data visualization, but that doesn’t mean it’s not valuable. The reason it is the most common is because most data has an element of time involved. Therefore, the first step in a lot of data analyses is to see how the data trends over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;determining-frequency&#34;&gt;Determining frequency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequency is also a fairly basic use of data visualization because it also applies to data that involves time. If time is involved, it is logical that you should determine how often the relevant events happen over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;determining-relationships-correlations&#34;&gt;Determining relationships (correlations)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying correlations is an extremely valuable use of data visualization. It is extremely difficult to determine the relationship between two variables without a visualization, yet it is important to be aware of relationships in data. This is a great example of the value of data visualization in data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;examining-a-network&#34;&gt;Examining a network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of examining a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;network&lt;/a&gt; with data visualization can be seen in market research. Marketing professionals need to know which audiences to target with their message, so they analyze the entire market to identify audience clusters, bridges between the clusters, influencers within clusters, and outliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scheduling&#34;&gt;Scheduling&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When planning out a schedule or timeline for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.projectsmart.co.uk/plan-and-schedule-more-complex-projects.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;complex&lt;/a&gt; project, things can get confusing. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gantt_chart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gantt chart&lt;/a&gt; solves that issue by clearly illustrating each task within the project and how long it will take to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;analyzing-value-and-risk&#34;&gt;Analyzing value and risk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determining complex metrics such as value and risk requires many different variables to be factored in, making it almost impossible to see accurately with a plain spreadsheet. Data visualization can be as simple as color-coding a formula to show which opportunities are valuable and which are risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-data-visualization-charts&#34;&gt;Types of data visualization charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand how data visualization can be used, let’s apply the different types of data visualization to their uses. There are numerous tools available to help create data visualizations. Some are more manual and some are automated, but either way they should allow you to make any of the following types of visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;line-chart&#34;&gt;Line chart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A line chart illustrates changes over time. The x-axis is usually a period of time, while the y-axis is quantity. So, this could illustrate a company’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.economicsonline.co.uk/Business_economics/Sales_and_revenue_maximisation.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sales&lt;/a&gt; for the year broken down by month or how many units a factory produced each day for the past week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;area-chart&#34;&gt;Area chart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An area chart is an adaptation of a line chart where the area under the line is filled in to emphasize its significance. The color fill for the area under each line should be somewhat transparent so that overlapping areas can be discerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bar-chart&#34;&gt;Bar chart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bar chart also illustrates changes over time. But if there is more than one variable, a bar chart can make it easier to compare the data for each variable at each moment in time. For example, a bar chart could &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patriotsoftware.com/accounting/training/blog/year-year-growth-calculate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;compare&lt;/a&gt; the company’s sales from this year to last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;histogram&#34;&gt;Histogram&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A histogram looks like a bar chart, but measures frequency rather than trends over time. The x-axis of a histogram lists the “bins” or intervals of the variable, and the y-axis is frequency, so each bar represents the frequency of that bin. For example, you could measure the frequencies of each answer to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.educational-business-articles.com/histogram-graph/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; question. The bins would be the answer: “unsatisfactory,” “neutral,” and “satisfactory.” This would tell you how many people gave each answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scatter-plot&#34;&gt;Scatter plot&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scatter plots are used to find correlations. Each point on a scatter plot means “when x = this, then y equals this.” That way, if the points trend a certain way (upward to the left, downward to the right, etc.) there is a relationship between them. If the plot is truly scattered with no trend at all, then the variables do not affect each other at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bubble-chart&#34;&gt;Bubble chart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bubble chart is an adaptation of a scatter plot, where each point is illustrated as a bubble whose area has meaning in addition to its placement on the axes. A pain point associated with bubble charts is the limitations on sizes of bubbles due to the limited space within the axes. So, not all data will fit effectively in this type of visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pie-chart&#34;&gt;Pie chart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pie chart is the best option for illustrating percentages, because it shows each element as part of a whole. So, if your data explains a breakdown in percentages, a pie chart will clearly present the pieces in the proper proportions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;gauge&#34;&gt;Gauge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gauge can be used to illustrate the distance between intervals. This can be presented as a round clock-like gauge or as a tube type gauge resembling a liquid thermometer. Multiple gauges can be shown next to each other to illustrate the difference between multiple intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;map&#34;&gt;Map&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the data dealt with in businesses has a location element, which makes it easy to illustrate on a map. An example of a map visualization is mapping the number of purchases customers made in each state in the U.S. In this example, each state would be shaded in and states with less purchases would be a lighter shade, while states with more purchases would be darker shades. Location information can also be very valuable for business leadership to understand, making this an important data visualization to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heat-map&#34;&gt;Heat map&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A heat map is basically a color-coded matrix. A formula is used to color each cell of the matrix is shaded to represent the relative value or risk of that cell. Usually heat map colors range from green to red, with green being a better result and red being worse. This type of visualization is helpful because colors are quicker to interpret than numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;frame-diagram&#34;&gt;Frame diagram&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frame diagrams are basically tree maps which clearly show hierarchical relationship structure. A frame diagram consists of branches, which each have more branches connecting to them with each level of the diagram consisting of more and more branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective data visualization is the crucial final step of data analysis. Without it, important insights and messages can be lost. Import.io understands the importance of data visualization, which is why it’s included in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.import.io/product/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Web Data Integration&lt;/a&gt; solution. Not only does Web Data Integration &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.import.io/product/extract/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;extract&lt;/a&gt; the data your organization needs from anywhere on the web, it takes that data all the way through the data analysis process of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.import.io/product/prepare/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;preparation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.import.io/product/integrate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;integration&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.import.io/product/insights/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;consumption&lt;/a&gt;, giving you easily consumable charts and graphs to gain insights from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A data visualization of unique words used by three central characters in the Game of Thrones book series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./game-of-thrones.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;here-is-the-list-of-the-blogs-to-follow&#34;&gt;Here is the list of the Blogs to follow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story telling with Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information is Beautiful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flowing Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualizing Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Junk Charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pudding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Plus Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphic Detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any Chart Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tableau Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to become a Data Scientist | A step by step guide</title>
      <link>/post/guide-to-become-a-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/guide-to-become-a-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Becoming a Data Scientists is an exciting path, but you cannot learn data science within one year or six months—instead, it’s a lifetime process that you have to follow with proper dedication and hard work. To guide your journey, the skills outlined here are the first you must acquire to become a data scientist.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of resources and links out there, but often we get confused on which resources to follow. Don’t worry, I have got you covered. I have attached the links to several YouTube channels, blogs, courses, and other websites that I found appropriate for a beginner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use the Data Science Community Websites Like Analytics Vidhya and Kaggle for implementing your learning and getting hands-on experience in Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./guide-become-data-scientist.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none d-xl-none &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-1-choose-a-programming-language-python--r&#34;&gt;STEP 1: Choose A Programming Language (Python / R)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-2-statistics&#34;&gt;STEP 2. Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-3-learn-sql&#34;&gt;STEP 3: Learn SQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-4-data-cleaning&#34;&gt;STEP 4. Data Cleaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-5-exploratory-data-analysis&#34;&gt;STEP 5: Exploratory Data Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-6-learn-machine-learning-algorithms&#34;&gt;STEP 6: Learn Machine Learning Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-7-practice-on-analytics-vidhya-and-kaggle&#34;&gt;Step 7: Practice On Analytics Vidhya and Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-choose-a-programming-language-python--r&#34;&gt;STEP 1: Choose A Programming Language (Python / R)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step while starting the Data Science Journey is to get familiar with a programming language. Between the two, Python is the most preferred coding language and is adopted by most Data Scientists. It is easy to understand, versatile, and supports various in-built libraries such as Numpy, Pandas, MatplotLib, Seaborn, Scipy, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rfscVS0vtbwl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FreeCodeCamp’s Python Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/learn/python&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kaggle’s Python Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZoTAELRMXVNUL99R4bDlVYsncUNvwUBB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Krish Naik’s Python Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/dataprofessor-udemy-python-ds&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Udemy’s Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/python&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Coursera Python Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt; While learning Python, one should know essential Python variables, data types, OOPs concepts, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-statistics&#34;&gt;STEP 2. Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For becoming a Data Scientist, having knowledge of statistics and probability is as essential as having salt in food. Knowing them will help the data scientists interpret large data sets, get insights from them, and analyze them better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zRUliXuwJCQ&amp;amp;list=PLZoTAELRMXVMhVyr3Ri9IQ-t5QPBtxzJO&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Krish Naik’s Statistics Playlist&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/statistics-for-data-science-python&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Coursera Statistics Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.khanacademy.org/math/statistics-probability&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Khan Academy Statistics And Probability Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xxpc-HPKN28&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FreeCodeCamp Statistics Course&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt; Statistics provides the ideas about Mean, Median, Mode, Range, Variance, Standard Deviation, Graphs or Plotting, Populations, and Samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-learn-sql&#34;&gt;STEP 3: Learn SQL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structured Query Language (SQL) is used for extracting and communicating with large databases. One should focus on understanding the different types of normalization, writing nested queries, using co-related questions, group-by, performing join operations, etc., on the data and extract in raw format. This data will then further be cleaned either in Microsoft Excel or by using Python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HXV3zeQKqGY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Freecodecamp SQL&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/learn/intro-to-sql&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intro To SQL By Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/learn/advanced-sql&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Advanced SQL By kaggle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BPHAr4QGGVE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Edureka’s SQL Playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt; In SQL, one should know about creating tables, inserting data, updating data, deleting data, and performing some basic query operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-data-cleaning&#34;&gt;STEP 4. Data Cleaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Data Scientist is given a project, the majority of the time goes into cleaning the data set, removing unwanted values, handling missing values. It can be achieved by using some inbuilt python libraries like Pandas and Numpy.
One should also know how to manipulate data using Microsoft Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://realpython.com/python-data-cleaning-numpy-pandas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blog — Cleaning Data Using Python&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RdTozKPY_OQ&amp;amp;t=2984s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Edureka’s Microsoft Excel Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/learn/pandas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Learning Pandas By Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt; In Microsoft Excel, you should know basic data filtering or sorting, Functions or Formulas, Vlookup, Pivot table and charts, and Tables, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-exploratory-data-analysis&#34;&gt;STEP 5: Exploratory Data Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploratory data analysis is the essential part when talking about data science. The data scientist has many tasks, including finding data patterns, analyzing data, finding the appropriate trends in the data and obtaining valuable insights, etc., from them with the help of various graphical and statistical methods, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A) Data Analysis using Pandas and Numpy
B) Data Manipulation
C) Data Visualization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pKsGE7wqQks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intro To EDA By Code Heroku’s&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/analytics-vidhya/exploratory-data-analysis-iris-dataset-4df6f045cda&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blog — Performing EDA on Iris Data Set&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/probability-theory-statistics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Coursera Course On EDA, Statistics, Probability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./types-of-plots-in-seaborn-python-librabry.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-learn-machine-learning-algorithms&#34;&gt;STEP 6: Learn Machine Learning Algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Google, “Machine learning is a method of data analysis that automates analytical model building. It is a branch of artificial intelligence based on the idea that systems can learn from data, identify patterns and make decisions with minimal human intervention.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the most crucial step in a life cycle of a data scientist where one has to build various models using machine learning algorithms and should be able to predict and come with the most optimum solution to solve any problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machine Learning By Andrew NG&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9jA0KjS7V_c&amp;amp;list=PLZoTAELRMXVPGU70ZGsckrMdr0FteeRUi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deep Learning By Krish Naik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/learn/intro-to-machine-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intro To ML By Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EqRsD3gqeCo&amp;amp;list=PLZoTAELRMXVOnN_g96ayzXX5i7RRO0QhL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machine Learning By Krish Naik&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/deep-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Coursera Deep Learning Specialization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./machine-learning-landscape.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-7-practice-on-analytics-vidhya-and-kaggle&#34;&gt;Step 7: Practice On Analytics Vidhya and Kaggle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After acquiring the basics of Data Science, now it’s time to get hands-on experience in its part. There are many online platforms, like Kaggle and Analytics Vidhya, that can provide you with hands-on experience with both beginner and advanced level data sets. They can help you to understand various machine learning algorithms, different analyzing techniques, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow the below approach to know how effectively you can use these platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start by first downloading the datasets and analyzing the data, and implementing all the different techniques you have learned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, you can check on other people’s notebooks and understand how they have solved a particular problem or gained insights from the data. (This method will certainly make you more confident and help to improve your knowledge.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you are confident enough, you can participate in Competitions organized by both Kaggle and Analytics Vidhya. This will not only help you to sharpen your skills in Data Science but also to learn Data Science better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/adityaagarwal68/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Aditya Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;, Graduate Student at Northeastern U&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 20 YouTube Channels to Learn Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/top-20-youtube-channels-for-datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/top-20-youtube-channels-for-datascience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knew YouTube would become so influential in our lives when it was launched back in 2005? Today after 15 years, it is known to be the best platform from which millions of people all around the world get enlighten with anything that anyone can possibly think of. There are thousands popular of YouTube channels out there today. But are there any dedicated YouTube channels for developers do you know about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even all the stats and number says it all about the popularity of YouTube in today’s time. And it didn’t take too long to become the second most popular website of the world right after its giant partner Google. Today one can find the YouTube app in every known device, starting from smartphones, tablets to a smart television, and any other streaming devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As this platform is a part of all our lives now so many people simply creating and sharing videos for it made fortune out of it. And today many YouTube channels have become really popular for a number of reasons. Now the medium &amp;amp; reach of YouTube has become so big &amp;amp; vast that this is a place where you can get audiences for anything that you want to teach or share useful&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today we are going to highlight some of the most prominent Data Science based YouTube channels for developers. But also for the general non-techy learners So keep reading to get introduced with some of the most famous YouTube channels dedicated mostly to Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;You Tube Channels&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Tech with Tim&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11. 365Data Science&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2. Sentdex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12. Edureka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. Corey Schafer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13. Data School&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4. Python Programmer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14. Data Camp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5. Keith Gali&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15. Siraj Raval&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. Andreas Kretz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16. Great learning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7. Free Code Camp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17. Krish Naik&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8. Springboard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18. David Langer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Data Science Dojo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19. StatQuest with Josh Stamer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10. 3Blue1Brown&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20. CS Dojo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study: Analytics and Data Science Jobs in India: June 2021</title>
      <link>/post/analytics-datascience-aims/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/analytics-datascience-aims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;C:%5CUsers%5Cresearch%5CDocuments%5Cimage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-analytics-job-report-presented-by-analytics-india-magazine-aim-provides-a-broad-study-of-the-data-science-job-landscape--covering-profiles-and-roles-that-require-analytics-competencies-and-skills&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The analytics job report, presented by Analytics India Magazine (AIM), provides a broad study of the data science job landscape – covering profiles and roles that require analytics competencies and skills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;report&#34;&gt;Report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research provides a comprehensive view of the talent market that was affected by the Covid-19 pandemic and its recovery since the lockdown restrictions were lifted. The report highlights the upswing in analytics jobs in the post-pandemic world and factors that have led to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report also outlines which functional analytics skills and programming languages are currently most in-demand in the market. The report provides insights for recruiters and hiring companies to study the demand for skills across the analytics function. They can identify and close any capability gaps across workforces. By highlighting the talent hotspots in the country, the report enables organization&amp;rsquo;s to build a steady talent pipeline from various regions or cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​	This Job Study is a holistic analysis of the Indian Analytics and Data Science jobs and skills landscape. This study/report covers the top job trends in the analytics space, specifically open jobs at a given point in time. It provides a detailed break-up and analysis of jobs by certain criteria, such as cities, industries, experience levels, technologies/tools, and salary hierarchies. The report provides details and analysis of the types of companies that are recruiting key talent in the data science domain. The report identifies reasons for significant shifts or changes in hiring trends across the criteria defined above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;top-trends-in-analytics-and-data-science&#34;&gt;Top Trends in Analytics and Data Science&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Data Science Job Trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs by Cities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs By Sector Or Industry (Excluding Analytics Jobs In The IT Sector)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience Requirement For Analytics Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs By Tools &amp;amp; Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salaries Advertised For Analytics Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics Jobs By Company Type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are approximately &lt;strong&gt;138,000 jobs open in June 2021&lt;/strong&gt;, a 67.0% increase from June 2020 when the average of advertised analytics jobs reached the lowest due to the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This increase in job numbers can be mainly attributed to the backfilling activity of companies after they laid off many employees due to the lockdown in March 2020. It can also be attributed to the accelerated adoption of AI/data science in India, which is a direct result of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1xfefhElGqwHQ4wSUQFmLUTQGkd7aDBsZ/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the Report here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please find reports from previous years here:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-2020-by-great-learning-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-2019-by-great-learning-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-2018-by-edvancer-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/analytics-and-data-science-india-jobs-study-2017-by-edvancer-aim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/study-analytics-and-data-science-jobs-in-india-april-2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Originally Published in AIM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
